Hi, I'm Ben.

A JavaScript Engineer // Front End Developer // UX Developer.

Skills



Education



Node

Bachelor of Arts (Hons) Interactive Design

University Lincoln 2009 - 2012

Contact details

- benwhomsley+cv@gmail.com
- **\(\)** 07538227685
- Output
 United Kingdom

Summary

Highly experienced JavaScript engineer with over 10 years in the industry, specialising in front-end development and user experience. Skilled in React & Next.js and modern web technologies. Passionate mentor with strong leadership skills in technical teams.

Professional Experience

Student Beans / Pion

2022 - present

Senior JavaScript Engineer // Current JavaScript Engineer // ~ 2 years

Currently part of the team that builds and maintains the web platform for the #1 student loyalty network. As well as working on other internal and external projects, my role also extends to mentoring other engineers and helping them grow in their careers.

Electroneum

2017 - 2022

UX Developer // ~ 5 years

Worked as part of a startup team building a new digital ecosystem and launching one of the most successful crypto projects of it's time. Leading the UX unit, we brought a revolutionary new digital eco system to market giving unbanked people in emerging economies access to a digital payment system.

Creative agencies

2012 - 2017

UI/UX Designer // ~ 2 years
Web & Application Designer // ~ 1 years
Senior Digital & Creative Designer// ~ 1 years

During this time I worked across three separate creative agencies working on a range of different products and mediums, ranging from print collateral for real estate marketing, to performance management apps for professional sports organisations (Team GB Taekwondo, Saracens rugby club, ECB Cricket and many more), to custom social media management dashboards.